nybooks.com 2019-10-17

# Privacy statement | The New York Review of Books

The New York Review of Books is committed to protecting your privacy. In order to fully understand your rights, we encourage you to read this privacy statement. This policy covers your communications through this site with The New York Review of Books magazine, New York Review Books, and The Reader’s Catalog. Please direct questions regarding this statement to [data-protection-manager@nybooks.com](mailto:data-protection-manager@nybooks.com).

**When does** _ **nybooks.com  **_ **or _nybooks.info  _collect my personal information?**

> The New York Review of Books gathers information from subscribers and visitors via subscription purchases, online book orders, voluntary registration on our website or email newsletter and marketing lists, cookie technology, and IP addresses.
> 
> **General Policy** : The New York Review of Books will not share your personal information with third parties unless you have consented to the disclosure or the disclosure is necessary to (1) provide a product or service you have specifically ordered from us, (2) comply with the law or with legal process, (3) protect and defend our rights and property, (4) protect our customers or users from misuse or unauthorized use of The New York Review of Books website, or (5) protect the personal safety or property of our customers or the public. We also disclose aggregated visitor statistics in order to describe our services and audience to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties. However aggregate data is not personally identifying and not traceable to you specifically
> 
> **Subscription Purchases and Website Registration** : When purchasing a subscription, we ask for your name, shipping and billing addresses, telephone number, and your credit card number and expiration date. This information is necessary for us to process your order regardless of method of purchase. We will not share any of this personal information without your consent, except as specifically stated in our General Policy above. You may optionally create an account on nybooks.com/nybooks.info in order to access content on our website. In order to create an account on nybooks.com/nybooks.info, we collect information that helps us identify you. On the initial registration page we ask for identifying information associated with your subscription account, as well as an email address and a password, in order to link your subscription account to your website access level. On subsequent visits, your email and password are required to sign in and access content on nybooks.com.
> 
> **Email Newsletter and Marketing (if applicable):** With your permission, we may send you emails about content on our website, new products and other updates germane to The New York Review of Books, New York Review Books, and The Reader’s Catalog.  You may change your preferences or unsubscribe from email notifications at any time by clicking on the links at the bottom of any email you have received, or by contacting [data-protection-manager@nybooks.com](mailto:data-protection-manager@nybooks.com)  with your request.
> 
> **Cookies** : Cookies are small text files that can be used by websites to make a user’s experience more efficient. You can set your browser preferences to reject all cookies, but this will prevent you from using most customized services. We use cookies to grant access to paywalled content, to personalize content and ads, to provide social media features, and to analyze our traffic. We also share non-personally-identifying information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners who may combine it with other information that you’ve provided to them or that they’ve collected from your use of their services _.  _Your browser may also store third-party cookies when visiting nybooks.com. These will include cookies from third-party advertising services, such as Google AdSense, and certain website analytics services that allow nybooks.com to monitor traffic and improve the user’s experience.
> 
> **IP address** : An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer automatically when you use the Internet. When you visit a particular web page on _The New York Review of Books_ site, our server logs your IP address. We may log IP addresses for the purposes of systems administration, or to report information in aggregate form to our retail partners and advertisers (e.g., how many visitors logged in to our website) in a form that is not personally identifying. If you are accessing the website via an Institutional Subscription, we also use IP addresses to identify access levels to nybooks.com.

**What are my options to control the use of my personal information?**

> Most browsers can be configured to reject cookies or alert you when cookies are being sent. You may cancel your registration to The New York Review of Books and/or request the removal of your personal information from our records by sending an email to [data-protection-manager@nybooks.com](mailto:data-protection-manager@nybooks.com) . We will reply to your email to confirm your request. After you respond affirmatively, we will remove your information from our database. Residual information may remain in our archives and records, but this information will not be used for a commercial purpose. We reserve the right to maintain information on registered users who have violated our terms and conditions, or who have had their access to The New York Review of Books blocked, in order to detect repeat offenders.

**Subscription Lists:**

> Occasionally we make our US subscriber postal list available to companies that sell goods and services we believe would interest our readers. We adhere strictly to the Direct Marketing Association’s Ethical Business Practices. For information about these practices, visit the Direct Marketing Association’s site at <https://thedma.org/accountability/ethics-and-compliance/dma-ethical-guidelines/>. If you would prefer not to receive such mailings, please email [nyrsub@nybooks.info](mailto:nyrsub@nybooks.info) and include your full name and mailing address and customer number if available. We never share email addresses with third parties.

**Kids and Parents:**

> This site is not intended for use by children under 16 years of age, and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from them. If you are between the ages of 16 and 18, you must have your parent’s permission to access and use our services. If you are a parent or guardian and learn that your child has provided us with personally identifiable information without your consent, please alert us, and we will promptly take steps to delete such information and terminate the child’s account.

**California Privacy Rights:**

> California law permits visitors who are California residents to request once per year certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of personal information to third parties for such third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [data-protection-manager@nybooks.com](mailto:data-protection-manager@nybooks.com).

**International Users:**

> If you are visiting from the New York Review of Books website from the European Union or other jurisdiction with laws governing data collection and transfer, please note that your data will be transferred to the United States and that, by using this site and providing your personal information, you are agreeing to this transfer of your information and to processing of your data globally in accordance with this privacy statement. Also, by choosing to visit the site and use our services you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this privacy statement will be governed by the laws of New York, United States, in accordance with our terms of use.  

**Change of Control or Sale:**

> We may share your personal information in the event our business is sold, as part of a merger or change in control, or in preparation for these events. Any successor entity will have the right to continue to use your personal information.

**What else should I know about my privacy?**

> Currently, we do not have forums, chat rooms, or other user-posted content.  If we add such features in the future, you should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose personal information online in a public area, that information might be collected and used by others. We do not control the actions of our visitors and registered users. If you disclose personal information in a forum or any other publicly accessible place on The New York Review of Books site, you do so at your own risk and you understand that your information may be collected and used by others.
> 
> Please remember that protection of your privacy begins with you. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any password you use to register, and you should always be careful and responsible whenever disclosing information online.
> 
> To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.
> 
> If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption.  Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.
> 
> The New York Review of Books website and newsletters may contain links to other sites operated by third parties. The New York Review of Books is not responsible for the actions of those third parties, the content of their websites, or any practices they may follow, and we encourage you to read the privacy policies of any other websites you might visit.

**How do I accept this privacy statement?**

> By using The New York Review of Books site and services, you signify your acceptance of this privacy statement. If you do not agree or are not comfortable with any policy described in this privacy statement, your only remedy is to discontinue use of The New York Review of Books site. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time. Your continued use of any portion of The New York Review of Books site following notification or posting of such changes, will constitute your acceptance of those changes. If you have questions or concerns about our specific policies, please send an email to [data-protection-manager@nybooks.com](mailto:data-protection-manager@nybooks.com) .
